S. Lane Faison papers, 1922-1981, bulk 1950-1976 AAA.faislane
Archives of American Art
- Artists Files, 1922-1976; Series 5; 1.5 Linear feet Box 3-5, 7
  - Calder, Alexander, 1952-1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 12.
  - Callery, Mary, 1950; 1952 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Canova, Antonio, 1940-1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Carpeaux, Jean Baptiste, circa 1958-circa 1966 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 13.
  - Cassatt, Mary, circa 1940-1976 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Cezanne, Paul, 1920-1973 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 14.
  - Constable, John, 1936-1963 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Corot, J.B.C., circa 1930-1965 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Couture, Thomas, circa 1930-1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Daumier, Honore Victorin, 1951-1970; 1930 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - David, Jacques Louis, 1971; circa 1930-1940 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Davidson, Jo, circa 1948 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Degas, Edgar, 1934-1976 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Delacroix, Eugene, 1930-1972 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Despiau, Charles, circa 1940 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Dispirito, Henry, circa 1940-1976 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Eakins, Thomas, circa 1931-1976 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Ensor, James, circa 1957 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Epstein, Jacob, circa 1938-1959 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Forain, Jean Louis, circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Gauguin, Paul, 1933-1970 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Gavarini, Paul, 1949-1954 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Gericault, Theodore, 1934-1971 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Giacometti, Alberto, 1955-1971 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Gill, Eric, circa 1938 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Greenbaum, Dorothea, circa 1939 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Gros, circa 1963 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Guys, Constantin, circa 1950-1960 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Harnett, William, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Horwitt, Will, circa 1969 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Houdon, Jean-Antoine, 1938-1964 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 15.
  - Ingres, Jean Auguste Dominique, circa 1950-1973 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 16.
  - Jongkind, Johann B., circa 1970-1976 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - de La Tour, M. Quentin, circa 1930-1970 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Lachaise, Gaston, circa 1964-circa 1974 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Lassaw, Ibram, 1954; 1952 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Laurens, Henri, circa 1937 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Lawrence, Thomas, circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Lawrie, Lee, circa 1932-1938 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Le Nain, circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Lehmbruck, Wilhelm, circa 1974 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Liberman, Alexander, circa 1971 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Lipton, Seymour, circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Macmonnies, Frederick, circa 1922-1936 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Maillol, Aristide, circa 1971; 1929-1941 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Manet, Edouard, 1972; 1949-1957 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Manship, Paul, circa 1937; circa 1951 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Marini, Marino, 1950; 1956 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Mestrovic, Ivan, circa 1930-1970 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Milles, Carl, 1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 17.
  - Millet, J.F., circa 1913; circa 1963 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Monet, Claude, 1949-1975 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Moore, Henry, 1940-1971 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 18.
  - Morisot, Berthe, circa 1970 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Munch, Edvard, 1950-1973 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Pissarro, Lucien, 1964-1973 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Prud'Hon, circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Puvis De Chavannes, Pierre, circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Redon, Odillon, circa 1972 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Renoir, Pierre Auguste, 1929-1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 19.
  - Rodin, Auguste, circa 1955-1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Rousseau, Henri, 1945-1949 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Rousseau, Theodore, circa 1963 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Saint-Gaudens, Augustus, circa 1937 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Sargent, John Singer, circa 1938-1964 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Seurat, Georges, circa 1957-1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Sisley, Alfred, circa 1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Signac, Paul, circa 1955 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Toulouse-Lautrec, 1938-1958 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 20.
  - Turner, J.M.W., circa 1950-1974 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Van Gogh, Vincent, circa 1935-1971 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 21.
  - Whistler, James Abbott McNeill, circa 1933-1972 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Zorach, William, circa 1938 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Oversized News Clippings from Box 4, Folder 7, 1952-1974 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Oversized Exhibition Catalog from Box 4, Folder 10, circa 1958-circa 1966 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Oversized News Clippings from Box 4, Folder 12, 1920-1973 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Oversized News Clippings from Box 4, Folder 37, 1938-1964 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Oversized News Clippings from Box 4, Folder 38, circa 1950-1973 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Oversized News Clippings from Box 4, Folder 56, 1936-1939 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Oversized Exhibition Catalogues from Box 4, Folder 59, 1940-1971 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Oversized Article from Box 5, Folder 1, 1929-1973 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Oversized Articles from Box 5, Folder 10, 1938-1958 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Oversized Magazine and Articles from Box 5, Folder 12, circa 1935-1971 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Printed Materials, circa 1935-1980; Series 6; 0.5 Linear feet Box 6, 7
  Printed materials consist of exhibition catalogs, bulletins, reports, news clippings, press releases, magazines and other miscellaneous printed matter.
  There is a copy of the Report on the Committee on the Visual Arts at Harvard University which examined the role of the arts in the curriculum. The report was by the Harvard Committee, whose chair was philanthropist and later Smithsonian regent John Nicholas Brown and the executive secretary was Faison. During World War II, President Roosevelt appointed Brown to General Eisenhower’s staff as Special Cultural Advisor and the civilian head of the Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives Section. Brown also argued against the removal of German-owned artworks to the United States in 1945.
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1937; 1955-1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Williams College, 1954-1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Museum Bulletins, 1966-1974; 1940 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Williams College Bulletins, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Museum of Modern Art Annual Report, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Report of the Committee on the Visual Arts at Harvard University, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - News Clippings: World War II, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 22.
  - News Clippings written by Faison, 1955-1959 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - News Clippings, 1956-1982 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, Folder 23.
  - Press Releases, 1959-1974 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Williams College Alumni Review Magazine, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1937-1971 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Undated Miscellaneous, circa 1935-1980 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Oversized News Clippings from Box 6, Folder 7, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Oversized News Clippings from Box 6, Folder 9, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 23)